CURRICULUM VITAE

MR.BENARD NYAGA MURIUKI

P.O BOX 662, Embu-Kenya, Telephone number: +254-0724272817

benardnyaga@gmail.com.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth: 14th Feb 1989

Nationality: Kenyan

I.D Number: 27913573

County: Embu.

District: Mbeere south.

Languages: English, Kiswahili, kimbeere and Chinese,

Sex: male

Marital Status: Married.

Age: 30 years

Phone no: 0724272817

Email address: benardnyaga@gmail.com

QUALIFICATION SUMMARY

I hold a Bachelor of Science Degree in Civil engineering with four years' experience in Engineering and Information, Communication and Technology related practice. Am highly knowledgeable and skillful in the use of numerous computer softwares such as MS-Office, AutoCAD, ArcGIS, Archi-CAD, Artlantis. I am also highly conversant in computer programming, trouble shooting, networking and digital communication.

CAREER STATEMENT

To practice my professionalism in work that will enable me to exploit my potential skills as well as improve my capacities towards sustainable development in achieving new heights for the organization. I am self-motivated, committed and determined in achieving my goals, firm sense of responsibility and capacity to work under pressure.

CAREER SUMMARY

- Building and structural engineering.
- -Traffic, transportation & highway engineering.
- Computer Aided Design.
- Communication and Information Technology.
- Project & construction management.

EDUCATION AND ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

2010- April 2015 KENYATTA UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science civil engineering Graduated with 2nd class upper division

2005-2008 KANGARU SCHOOL-EMBU COUNTY

KCSE scored B+

1994-2004 ST MARY'S ACADEMY MUNYORI-MBEERE SOUTH

KCPE scored 388/500 marks

OTHERS

March 2014 KENYATTA UNIVERSITY

Certificate in ArcGIS & Remote sensing

Passed in Distinction

May-Sep 2013 BELL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Certificates in AutoCAD - Distinction

May-Sep 2012 BELLS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

Certificate in ArchiCAD - Distinction

Jan-May 2009 ACHIEVERS COLLEGE EMBU

Certificate in computer packages-Distinction

WORK EXPERIENCE.

1. STATE DEPARTMENT OF INFRASTRUCTURE.

Position: Assistant Engineer I (Materials)

Period: 2017 – Current.

Responsibilities

- Managing and overseeing testing of construction materials.
- Preparing engineering Reports.
- Communicating with project participants through emails and phone conversations.
- Giving engineering advice on the use of construction materials.
- Doing research on construction materials and technologies.
- Co-ordination of quality control activities.

2. KENYA URBAN ROADS AUTHORITY.

Project: Lot 11 - Improvement of woodlands-Lenana road junction, James Gichuru-Gitanga road Junction and State house road-Arboretum road junction

Position: Site Engineer. **Period:** 2016 – Oct 2017.

Responsibilities

- Supervision of all construction activities.
- Co-ordination and management of Engineer's site staff.
- Communicating with project participants through emails and phone conversations.

- Preparation of project's daily, weekly and monthly reports.
- Coordination of service providers in communication data, power and water.
- Doing Computer Aided Designs.

3. ELEGANT PROPERTIES (K) LTD.

Project: Design and construction supervision of the upcoming 16th floors SKYNNEST apartment building in Westland's opposite Kentrail towers.

Position: Structural engineer.

Period: 2016. Responsibilities

- Design and specification of building projects i.e. (the upcoming 16th floors SKYNNEST apartment building) in Westland's opposite Kentrail towers.
- Production of structural drawings using AutoCAD & Archi Cad.
- Doing structural redesigns and drawings modifications for the contactor on site.
- Construction supervision of steel fixing and concrete casting works.
- Calculating quantities of steel, cement, sand and aggregate before ordering from the suppliers.
- Preparation of weekly work progress reports.

4. CIVOTECH ASSOCIATES (K) LTD.

Company description: Civotech Associates consulting engineers ltd is a Kenyan engineering Consultancy Company that specializes in design and construction supervision of buildings, roads and water-sanitation projects.

Project: Design and construction supervision of Embu town storm water drainage project.

Position: Assistant engineer. **Period:** 2015 – Dec 2016.

Responsibilities

- Production of drainage drawings using Autocad.
- GIS Mapping of the construction work using ArcGIS.
- Design of lateral drainage lines using AutoCAD and excel.
- Design of storm water drainage facilities i.e. channels and culverts.
- Preparation of water supply inception and detailed design reports.

5. RUNJI & PARTNERS CONSULTING ENGINEERS & PLANNERS LTD.

Project: Water supply and sanitation improvement for informal settlements in Eastland's Nairobi; (Mathare, Huruma, Kayole and Kariobangi).

Position: Civil engineering trainee. **Period:** April – September 2014.

Responsibilities

 Production of water supply and sewerage construction drawings using Autocad basic and Autocad civil 3D.

- Redesign of lateral sewer lines using Autocad civil 3D and excel.
- Supervision of water supply and sewerage construction contractor's work at the site.
- Conduction of tests such as leakage and pressure tests.
- Making weekly and monthly progress reports.

6. UPGRO RESEARCH- UNLOCKING GROUND WATER POTENTIAL RESEARCH FOR KILIFI COUNTY-KENYA.

Research description: The research was an underground water research project led by Prof Joy Obando of Kenyatta University, School of engineering and department of geography. The research involved mapping boreholes and wells, measuring water levels and determining water quality of boreholes and wells along the coastline of Kilifi County in Kenya.

Position: Student Assistant Researcher.

Period: January-April 2014.

Responsibilities

- Use of GPS receivers to take boreholes and wells location.
- Determining boreholes and wells depth and water rest levels using a dipper.
- Analysis of boreholes and wells GPS data using ArcGIS software.
- Checking and overseeing maintenance of research computers.

7. CHINA WU-YI CONSTRUCTION COMPANY.

Project: KCB plaza in upper hill and china WuYi office building projects in Hurlingum-Nairobi

Position: Student engineering attaché.

Period: April-Sep 2013.

Responsibilities

- Was involved in construction supervision.
- Was involved in engineering designs.
- Was involved in engineering surveys.

8. KENYATTA UNIVERSITY.

Project: Construction of K.U referral hospital, the new administration block and extension of Bio-chemistry department buildings projects.

Position: Student engineering attaché.

Period: May - Sep 2012.

Responsibilities

- Interpretation of drawings to the masons, carpenters and steel fixers.
- Estimation of volumes of sand, ballast and cement.
- Calculation of steel quantity using structural drawings and bar bending schedules.
- Participated in supervision of structural reinforcement works.

ACHIEVEMENT AND LEADERSHIP

Jan 2014-Feb 2015:

Secretary General- Embu County Kenyatta University Student Association (ECKUSA).

Jan 2014- Feb 2015:

Chairperson – Kenyatta University Mbeere Students Association.

MEMBERSHIP

- Graduate Engineer Engineers Board of Kenya
- Graduate Member Institute of Engineers of Kenya

SKILLS PROFILE

- Excellent interpersonal and presentation skills.
- Excellent analytical skills and leadership skills.
- Excellent communication skills.
- Self-driven and team player.
- Self-motivated and organized professional.
- Attentive to detail and very organized.
- Result oriented and proficient in computer usage.

HOBBIES

- Watching mega-projects construction documentaries.
- Volunteering in community service.
- Participating in sports; playing badminton.

REFEREES

Eng.Florence C. Ambuche,

Assistant Resident Engineer,

Lot 11 - Improvement of woodlands-Lenana road junction, James Gichuru-Gitanga road Junction and State house road-Arboretum road junction,

Kenya Urban Roads Authority.

Phone no: 0723948004, Email: fambuche@kura.go.ke.

Eng. Dennis Mugendi Mutegi,

Assistant Resident Engineer,

Water & sanitation improvement project-(Eastlands Nairobi),

Runji and partners consulting engineers,

Phone no: 0722934868,

Email: mugendidn@gmail.com.

Prof. Joy Obando,

Water & sanitation engineering professor,

UPGRO-Lead Researcher.

Kenyatta University School of engineering,

0722966134.

Email: obandojoy@gmail.com.

DECLARATION

I certify that all the information given in this resume is true and complete to the best of my knowledge. I authorize the recipient hereof to verify the information provided in this curriculum vitae should the need arise.

Mr. Benard Nyaga Muriuki. June, 2019.